A useful feature within Windows
is the ability to compress files
and folders to save disk space.
This isn't as much of an issue as it is
to be as, most hard drives have a large
capacity, there are a large capacity
flash drives and also cloud storage.
However you may still wish to send a
file or a folder to an email recipient
or archive it and compressing the file
or folder will save some disk space.
So just to demonstrate how
that can be done, I'm going to
use the WP2 assessment folder.
Now, if I move my mouse over that,
and you can see that the information
is that it's 322 kilobytes in size.
So the files within
that are 322 kilobytes.
What I'm going to do is I'm going
to compress that by right-clicking
on the folder and then select Send
To, and then when I select Send To I
click on compressed zipped folder and
that will then zip that folder up.
So as you can see it has basically
made a duplicate of that folder,
and it is identified with a
little zipper down the middle.
Now as you can see, I've hovered
my mouse over it, and it's telling
me that it's 172 kilobytes in size.
So it has reduced the size of
the files within there by half.
So, while that doesn't seem very large
it could be a case of that you could
have a folder that contained information
that is five, 10, 15, 20 megabytes, and
then that can be reduced, which would
then make it easier to attach and save
disk space if you are archiving it.